# BRYAN PEARSON

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

University: University of Central Florida

College Unit: College of Engineering and Computer Science (CECS)

Address: Research 1, University of Central Florida

Email: bpearson@knights.ucf.edu

## **BIOGRAPHY**

Bryan Pearson joined the Department of Computer Science at the University of Central Florida as a Ph.D student in August 2018, under the supervision of Dr. Xinwen Fu. He received his B.S. in Computer Science from Stetson University (2014), with minors in Physics and Mathematics.

Bryan's research interests include security and forensics of wireless sensor networks (WSN) and Internet of Things (IoT) systems, networking quality of service (QoS), and IoT scalability. He has been publishing in several conferences and journals including IEEE International Conference on Communications, SoutheastCon, INFOCOM, and MDPI Sensors.

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Central Florida

August 2018 - Present

Ph.D in Computer Science

Focus: Internet of Things (IoT) security

Advisor: Dr. Xinwen Fu

Stetson University

May 2018 GPA: 3.507 / 4.000 B.S. in Computer Science

Minors in Math and Physics Advisor: Dr. Daniel Plante

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

- IoT security and forensics
- Applications and solutions of WSN and IoT
- Networking and computer systems QoS
- Light cryptography implementation and optimizations

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Assistant August 2018 - Present

Florida IT Pathways to Success (Flit-Path)

Graduate Research Assistant August 2018 - August 2019

University of Central Florida, Department of Computer Science

Instructor June 2017 - July 2018

ID Tech Camps

Clerical Assistant May 2017 - June 2018

Stetson University, Departments of English/Computer Science

# SCHOLARSHIPS AND GRANTS

University of Central Florida

Graduate Presentation Fellowship Spring 2020 IEEE ICC NSF Student Travel Grant April 2019 Graduate Presentation Fellowship February 2019 Graduate ORC Doctoral Fellowship Flit-Path NSF Grant August 2018 August 2018

### Stetson University

Presidential Scholarship Federal Pell Grant Bright Futures FASA August 2014 - May 2018 August 2014 - May 2018 August 2014 - May 2018

#### ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

### Committee Membership

1. Web Chair, SecureComm Organizing Committee

2019

## Peer Reviewed Manuscripts

- 1. TGSM: Towards Trustworthy Group-based Service Management for Social IoT. *IEEE Internet of Things Journal*.
- 2. Missing value imputation for Industrial IoT sensor data with large gaps. IEEE Internet of Things Journal.
- 3. Online Optimization of Wireless Powered Mobile-Edge Computing for Heterogeneous Industrial Internet of Things. *IEEE Internet of Things Journal*.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. B. Pearson, D. Plante. Secure Deployment of Containerized IoT Systems. *In proceedings of IEEE South-eastCon 2020*. Raleigh, North Carolina. Mar. 2020.
- 2. Y. Zhang, J. Weng, Z. Ling, B. Pearson, X. Fu. BLESS: A BLE Application Security Scanning Framework. In proceedings of IEEE INFOCOM 2020 - IEEE Conference on Computer Communications (INFOCOM). Beijing, China. Apr. 2020.
- 3. B. Pearson, L. Luo, C. Zou, J. Brian, Y. Jin, X. Fu. Building a Low-cost and State-of-the-art IoT Security Hands-on Laboratory. 2nd IFIP Internation Internet of Things (IoT) Conference. Oct. 31-Nov. 1, 2019. (Invited Paper.)
- 4. C. Gao, L. Luo, Y. Zhang, B. Pearson, X. Fu. Microcontroller Based IoT System Firmware Security: Case Studies. *In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Industrial Internet (ICII)*, Orlando, FL, Nov. 2019. (Best Paper Award.)
- 5. B. Pearson, L. Luo, Y. Zhang, R. Dey, Z. Ling, M. Bassiouni, and X. Fu. On Misconception of Hardware and Cost in IoT Security and Privacy. *In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC)*, Shanghai, China, May 2019.
- 6. L. Luo, Y. Zhang, B. Pearson, Z. Ling, H. Yu, and X. Fu. On the Security and Data Integrity of Low-Cost Sensor Networks for Air Quality Monitoring. *Sensors (Basel)*. Dec. 2018.
- 7. N. Domingo, B. Pearson, and Y. Jin. Exploitations of Wireless Interfaces Via Network Scanning. *In proceedings of IEEE International Conference on Computing, Networking and Communications (ICNC)*, Santa Clara, CA, 2017.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, Python, Java, R, PHP, JavaScript, MatLab

Software: Arduino IDE, ESP-IDF, MatLab, Splunk, Wireshark, Mongoose OS, AWS, Google Cloud, Microsot Azure, Node.js, Apache, Nginx, Spark, Docker, Kubernetes

#### REFERENCES

**Dr. Xinwen Fu** (Primary Advisor)

Associate Professor of Computer Science

Email: xinwenfu@ucf.edu

**Dr. Cliff Zou** (Co-advisor)

Associate Professor of Computer Science

Email: changchun.zou@ucf.edu

University of Central Florida

University of Central Florida